Department of Kinesiology. Reports and Proposals. 1936-1977.
UCLA Library Special Collections
Department of Kinesiology. Reports and Proposals.
1936-1977
University Archives Record Series 335
UCLA Library Special Collections
0.8 linear ft. (2 boxes)
Record Series 335 contains reports and proposals generated by members of UCLA's Department of Kinesiology. Files include annual reports, conference presentations, studies, and proposals concerning departmental operations.
Department of Kinesiology
Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
Historical Note
The current Department of Kinesiology trace its origins to the Department of Physical Education established in 1915 as a part of the Los Angeles Normal School. During the 1920s, the department's efforts were devoted to the training of Physical Education teachers and the administration of the Physical Education classes that were required of all undergraduates. In 1938, the department instituted a Master of Science program; and in 1947, a Doctorate of Education was added to the department's curriculum. During the 1950s and 1960s, several research laboratories were founded, including: the Human Performance Laboratory, Perception and Motor Learning Laboratory, and Underwater Research Laboratory. In 1973, the Department of Physical Education changed its name to the Department of Kinesiology. A PhD program was instituted in 1979.
Scope and Content
Record Series 335 contains reports and proposals generated by members of UCLA's Department of Kinesiology. Files include annual reports, conference presentations, studies, and proposals concerning departmental operations. Reports regard curriculum development and requirements for various degree programs; administrative organization of the department; the role of physical education and kinesiology in the university; and prescribed ethics for staff members.
This is an inactive record series; no additional University records are expected to be added.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 3466862
- Annual Report - Department of Physical Education., 1956-1957. (Box 1)
- Antecedents of Competitiveness - Scanlan, T.K., n.d. (Box 1)
- Anxiety Inducing Factors in Competitive Youth Sports - Scanlan, Passer. (Box 1)
- California Junior College Study - General Info. and the Health Program., 1956 Sep. (Box 1)
- California Junior College Study - Recreation and Athletics., 1956 Sep. (Box 1)
- Chancellor's Special Committee on the Department of Physical Education., 1955 Jan. (Box 1)
- Children in Competition - Scanlan, T.K., 1977. (Box 1)
- Classroom and Office Buildings for Physical Education and Military Science., 1958 Jun. (Box 1)
- Contribution of the Department of P.E. to Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation., 1952 Jun. (Box 1)
- Contributions of Health Ed, Phys Ed and Recreation to Goals of General Ed., 1951. (Box 1)
- Curriculum Committee Report., 1944. (Box 1)
- Department of Kinesiology Organization and Adinistrative Evaluation - Woodruff., 1976 Jun 17. (Box 1)
- Education Policies of the Department of Physical Education., 1954. (Box 1)
- Factors which Influence Choice of Physical Education Activities by Students., n.d. (Box 1)
- The Effects of Success and Failure in a Competitive Situation - Scalan, F., 1976 Jul. (Box 1)
- The Physical Education Requirement - Morehouse, L., 1967 Dec. (Box 1)
- Course Changes in Physical Education - Proposed., n.d. (Box 2)
- Curriculum Coordinating Council - Reports - P.E. Curriculum., 1951-1952. (Box 2)
- Expected Competencies for Women P.E. Majors at the end of the 14th Grade., 1949 Dec. (Box 2)
- Graduate Students Guide Book., 1952. (Box 2)
- Human Patellar Tendon Rupture - Zernicke, Garhammer, and Jobe., 1976. (Box 2)
- Information Manual - School of Physical Education., 1936-1937. (Box 2)
- Instructional Module - Lower Extremity Injures in Skiing., 1977. (Box 2)
- Instructional Module - The Biomechanics of Ligaments., 1977. (Box 2)
- Interpretation of Prescribed Coursework in UCLA., 1964 May. (Box 2)
- Kinesiology as a Life Science: An Undergrad Curriculum - Zernicke, Gregor., 1977. (Box 2)
- M.S. Degree in P.E. - Proposal to Subcommittee of Graduate Council., 1967. (Box 2)
- Physical Education for General College Students in Selected American Universities., 1957 Jan. (Box 2)
- Principles, Policies and Procedures for Allocation of the Workload., 1955 Nov. (Box 2)
- Proposal for a PhD degree in the Kinesiology Department., 1968. (Box 2)
- Proposal for a Reinforced M.S. Degree in Physical Education., 1965 Sep. (Box 2)
- Sabbatical Leave Report - Hollingsworth, Cecil B., 1955-1956. (Box 2)
- Self Study Report of the Department of Physical Education., 1958. (Box 2)
- Single Motor Unit Control in M. Biceps Brachii - Zernicke, Robert., 1972. (Box 2)
- Status of Preparation in P.E. in the 3 Districts of the A.A.H.P.E.R., n.d. (Box 2)
- Sternberg - Reports of Dr. Bovard., 1938-1941. (Box 2)
- Study of Teaching Methods Used During the Academic Year., 1953-1954. (Box 2)
- Suggested Directions for Competition Research - Scanlan, T.K., n.d. (Box 2)
- Teching Load, Class Size and Instructional Costs., 1954 Nov. (Box 2)
- Tentative Statement on Staff Ethics and Relationships - Miller, Ben., 1952 Dec. (Box 2)
- The Need for a College Physical Education Requirement., n.d. (Box 2)
- The Physical Education Library Today and Tomorrow., 1961-1962. (Box 2)
- The Place of Camping in the College Service Program., 1952. (Box 2)
- The Subject Matter of Kinesiology - Morehouse, L., n.d. (Box 2)